Having arrived at the Ancient Capital Garm,
Akari and I headed for the cathedral
to see Archbishop Orwell.
Akari thinks that the ritual we're about to perform
is for sending her back to her own world.
But actually, it's for eliminating dangerous
otherworlders who possess Pure Concepts.
Menou! Come on, hurry!
Don't worry, we have plenty of time to see the sights.
Well, I want to spend as much time as I can with you!
Oh, Akari.
Ahh, that was so much fun!
You must be tired. Why don't you take a bath?
Yeah!
Oh, I know. Do you want to take one together?
We could wash each other!
"Wash each other"?
Akari, you're a little too intimate with people.
You should be careful.
What? That's not true!
Like I said before, meeting you feels like fate, Menou!
Okay.
I'm very offended if you think
I act like this with just anyone!
I only said what I said because I
like you so much, Menou!
Well, yeah... I know that.
Do you really, though?
Do you really get my overflowing desire to spend what
little time we have left as intimately as possible?
Come on, Menou! It'll bring us closer together!
Right, right. Just go take your bath, okay?
On your own, please.
You don't get it at all!
Jeez! You'd better not regret turning this down later!
Akari says she likes me so much, but tomorrow...
I'm going...
to kill her.
Episode 5: Goodbye
Menou!
Momo, thanks for taking the job.
It breaks my heart that I don't get to see you today!
Your Momo wants to feel your
warmth up close and in person!
Momo being the same as ever is kind of reassuring.
Is something the matter, Menou?
It's nothing.
So, how is it going with your investigation
on the missing women?
All good!
You know how Garm's a rotten city where they
bury anything that's not pretty underground?
That's a crude way of putting it, but you're right.
Rumor has it that anything shady is done
in the massive underground sewers,
so I interviewed some of the
homeless who live down there.
Brilliant, Momo. You know just where to look.
Hee hee! More praise, please!
Momo. Can we get on with this?
Sure.
So then, I found someone who
saw a shady group of people.
And the place where they saw them...
was near the former royal palace.
The former palace... That's Noblesse territory.
That agrees with your theory that the Noblesse
here might have something to do with it.
So I'm about to go look into that now.
I see. Make sure to be careful, Momo.
Of course!
I'm hoping for a nice big reward when I'm done!
All right, I'll think about it.
Then off I go!
A reward, huh?
It's true I ask so much of Momo all the time.
Maybe I should get her something for once.
It feels like I just got here!
But it's a nice place, your world over here.
I'm glad you feel that way.
Now that I know I can go back,
I wish I could have stayed a little longer.
I probably won't get the chance to come
to another world again, after all.
Oh come on, Akari.
Oh, a street vendor!
Let's take a look!
Handmade accessories?
Garm is famous for this pretty cloth.
You can buy them ready-made,
but why not make something yourself?
I'm not that good with my hands, actually...
I don't know...
I'll make something.
There, done.
Not bad.
Menou!
You made two,
which means there's one for each of us, right?
What? No.
Huh?! They're not?!
These are a gift for a junior of mine.
She always does so much for me-
Uh, Akari?
Menou, why are you like that sometimes?
I know you don't mean it, but still!
Um... So you're upset.
Well, yeah!
We're gonna say goodbye soon
and you're not getting me anything?
Fine, fine. Can I see this for a second?
There, done.
There, nice and cute.
You have such good taste, Menou!
I like that about you, too!
Thank you, Menou!
You're very welcome!
It's perfect for the ditzy flower-head you are,
if I do say so myself.
Wait, you just said something really mean, didn't you?!
Hello there, Miss Menou and Miss Akari Tokitou.
I've been expecting you.
Thank you for coming to greet us.
Off we go then, to the ceremonial hall.
Th-thank you for having me!
Wow.
A hidden passageway?
Not an easy find. Way to go, me!
Clearly, something's weird about this place.
This wall material looks like it's
used for some kind of ritual.
But what for?
Well, well. What a coincidence, Momo.
No way.
Fancy running into you here.
It seems we're destined to meet!
I wish she'd bite her tongue and die.
But why are you here?
This is beneath the former royal palace.
It's not a place a priestess should be.
I was asked to run an errand in
return for pilgrimage funds.
Though I doubt a little princess like you
would understand the concept of labor.
"Little princess"?
How delightfully adorable.
Feel free to call me Little Ashuna from now on.
Hmm. "Little princess."
Oh, ugh!
I went to the former royal palace once I arrived
in Garm and sensed something shady.
I think the knights here are hiding something.
Well, they're Noblesse, after all.
Quite the biting remark.
Anyway, I snuck into the heavily guarded area
beneath the palace and found you here.
The little princess is more intuitive than I thought.
So...
What kind of "errand" did they send you on?
Depending on the circumstances,
I think we could work together.
What, are you stupid? Why should I have to do that?
And could you stop following me, please?
Hey!
What do you think you're doing?!
You want me to kill you?!
It's because you keep neglecting me.
Ew, what?!
I knew it. Those ribbons are your weakness.
You protected those right away back on the train, too.
Do they remind you of some precious memory?
Perhaps they're a present... from someone?
A girl should have a sense of style.
The Master taught me that.
You look cute.
Really, you're unbearable.
Apparently you have no sense of tact, Little Princess.
Doesn't your family ever tell you that?
It would have been nice to have a
family who could say things like that.
Imply whatever you want. I don't want to hear about it.
Authenticate
[Open]
There, go on in.
I never knew a place like this existed under the cathedral!
Come, Miss Akari. You go to that altar.
Right.
Akari.
Menou.
Is this really goodbye?
I won't ever see you again?
That's right, unfortunately.
I wanted to spend more time with you, Menou.
I feel the same way, Akari.
But you shouldn't be here in this world.
It's fine.
You have nothing to worry about.
Even if there is any pain,
I'm sure it will only be for a moment.
Thank you, Menou.
Off I go, then.
Right. Akari...
Goodbye.
What's this?
A secret place for a ritual, perhaps?
Seems that way.
You've become awfully good friends with her.
Yes, that's how I acted towards her.
I see. This must be hard for you, Miss Menou.
I've killed so many before her.
She's no different than the others.
Or at least, I thought so...
My Master would never feel this way...
There's no need to compare yourself to your teacher.
That girl, Flare, always defied common sense,
for better or for worse.
You're in this world for a reason, you know.
You have a role to fulfill.
I hope you understand that.
I do.
Thank you for that.
My role right now is to see Akari's
death through to the end.
Record
Statues in the cardinal directions
and overlapping pentagrams...
This is definitely a teleportation test site.
Considering this thing is underneath the former palace...
It's undeniable proof that the
Noblesse of Garm were involved in heresy.
Perhaps the testing and preparations for the summoning
my father did were conducted here, as well.
Probably.
But really...
I'm amazed they managed to reproduce this
so well when it's exclusive Faust knowledge.
When they're only Noblesse.
I'm surprised you have such faith in your own people.
So they really just sent you on an errand?
I assumed you were on an internal investigation.
Excuse me? What do you mean by that?
As you say...
The Noblesse don't have the knowledge
or ability to make something like this.
As one of the Noblesse, I know that better than anyone.
So tell me, who does?
That's right, the Faust.
The Noblesse and the Faust
here are conspiring together.
The former palace and cathedral
are right next to each other.
They must have collaborated through
this underground passageway.
Such a major operation couldn't have
been conducted by the average priestess.
So, who do you suppose is behind this?
You don't mean...
Invoke
[Communication]
Disrupt
Communication
I've been blocked?!
Magecraft for communication?
That's exclusive to the Faust, no?
Do you have one of your people outside?
Will you be quiet for a moment?!
Disrupt
Communication
This is it!
I'm connected!
Menou! Watch out for her!
Well, it's almost time.
Yes.
Akari...
Momo?
Oh, is something the matter, Miss Menou?
Archbishop Orwell...
So she got past the communication interference?
I asked for the investigation so I
could separate the two of you,
but perhaps I underestimated the situation.
No matter, I'll dispose of you both either way.
Etheric Connect-Scripture,
3:1-Invoke
[And the oncoming enemy
did hear the toll of the bell.]
Those are... the three primary color gems?!
Menou?!
Akari, get out of here!
My scripture!
Okay, then...!
Menou!
Menou!!
Was that from the cathedral?
Menou!
Hold it, Momo!
I see...
They wouldn't allow intruders in here
unless they had prepared a trap.
It only makes sense.
An automa in dragon form and
a summoned demon, hmm?
Come Momo...
Why don't we cooperate against this threat?
It pisses me off, but sure, just this once!
What's that?
The missing women...
Red material...
And the summoning of otherworlders in the royal capital.
Then the one behind it all...
I still have a long way to go if I'm so easily
fooled by a slight show of kindness.
No need to feel discouraged.
The older you get,
you inevitably become more underhanded
and learn to manipulate the young.
You're levelheaded and capable for your age,
but you have yet to be as
vigilant or as underhanded as Flare.
It pains me to hear that advice.
Menou?! Menou!
May I ask what your reason is, for future reference?
Why would you, when you've earned
everyone's trust in becoming archbishop?
Of course you wouldn't understand.
All you do is kill, after all.
When you help too many people,
you come to loathe their pleas for help.
"Help... Help... Why are you not helping us?
We demand more..."
The clingy voices never leave me alone.
When no one is willing to help me, you see.
This... It's a protective barrier!
Getting an old woman to babble on might buy
you the time until your aide gets here to help.
Is that what you thought?
Well, that isn't happening.
So what were we talking about?
Ah yes, you wanted to know why I would do all this.
You see, my lower back has been
aching something terrible lately.
I can hardly get up in the morning.
Now at this age I've finally realized something.
I'm no holy woman.
I'm just an ordinary person who had
the time and energy to help others.
But who can blame me?
I've helped so many.
Can't I get a little something in return?
I deserve to use that girl's
Pure Concept to restore my youth!
Your objective is Akari's Pure Concept itself?!
Let me go! I need to help Menou!
Quiet down, otherworlder!
Stay still and this will soon be over.
All right, begin!
It was such perfect timing.
My experiment using young
girls wasn't getting anywhere.
I gave the Noblesse the means
to summon otherworlders
so that they would
overlook what I was doing here,
but who knew it would end up helping me like this?
Although I never expected Princess Ashuna
to come all the way out here.
Well, I suppose I have the Pure Concept of Time
at my disposal now,
so all's well that ends well, no?
I see...
I can see how someone like you who fears becoming
decrepit would want Akari's Pure Concept.
But even with your phenomenal skill in magecraft,
a Pure Concept isn't
something you can manipulate at will.
Goodness, Miss Menou.
That's why we have this ceremonial hall.
I suppose I can tell you.
That place was originally a test
site for erasing personalities.
"Erasing... personalities"?
A place for blanching a person's spirit and soul clean.
If you wipe an otherworlder's mind,
all that's left is the Pure Concept
to use as you wish, you see?
We sourced a fragment of White
from the Starhusk in the northern continent.
Not even an otherworlder can resist its
power to blanch everything out.
Akari!
Not to worry.
To use the Pure Concept effectively,
you are just what I need as quality magecraft material.
I'll use you along with her.
I only waited ten years because I needed you
to grow into a proper catalyst for my needs.
Still, I highly doubt you'll comply
without putting up a fight, so...
Primary Pseudo-concept
[Red]-Activate
[Primary Red, cElestIAL MeSSengER]
A red automa... And one in angel form, at that?
Considering you've lost your scripture,
perhaps this was overkill.
Well, I'll go easy on you, so come take it on.
Next episode: [Regression: Memories, Soul, Spirit].
Next Episode
[Regression: Memories, Soul, Spirit]